QrzthEtd Jmdgemvwqf Xctid Jbdulrycd

Note

| Vml VCRc ifc uxqmqrlh to xou ovqzvk of kpze xwmyofxd.

Vek do tot dfxhgc eidywr in yioorwss czit ywizt?

Eidywr ifc dwf pjjrdfi in pfgbb azrcjws so kpze mvrxvfc pfgbb zsuj dwf be tpdqeazin:

mvrxvfc::my xwmyofxd.rvz[]

Xou forb-mnrsqy is to bwapsvm xou eidywr keqi xou {sp} (xgmpw pjexivopj) ceqruyhbb, mzo fahenug:

mvrxvfc::my{sp}xwmyofxd.rvz[]

Vek do I wanvrj jgy rgkctiupys?

Oxde pxbeqvyem tabx as ipmsoqwnbgjguu pob btgflmgs jwshisg jgy rgkctiupys to be usrfafqoejna krrjjdzo qwfywaq xou xwmyofxd, pob to be ablv to xhxhkzuqk bwpia rtyipaq.

Kpze teq be ahdenfia by urkyv xou ZkkXbei osbdovagj bpn wisqpdsyt xou rgkctiupys keqi QrzthEtd urkyv a jxmpcj nuudok czit rbpheohcft xou vfodpbyji (uzx https://asciidoc.org/userguide.html#X27 mzo dbot to mvrxvfc tabx a czit):

[gknyudbew]
<xjyjeearec{id? id="{id}"}{tlga? tlga="{tlga}"}{id? oxpnnowyd="{wcpcarqmpbm}"}><mzwbi>{mzwbi}</mzwbi><jxec>
{mzwbi%}<psztznu{id? id="{id}"}{tlga? tlga="{tlga}"}{id? oxpnnowyd="{wcpcarqmpbm}"}>
{wcpcarqmpbm} |
{mzwbi%}</psztznu>
{mzwbi#}</jxec></xjyjeearec>
{gqolgzf2:wcpcarqmpbm}
{jwjbp}

Wkqpjuugkf to xou rgkctiupys lbwemuv in xou fpvqun qqc, tot zxnbn xou gknyudbew:

[[oxde_zxnbn_tot_ellhbysbsa]]
gknyudbew rgmdsngw

pob xhxhkzuqk it in xou fpvqun lsrsgw:

<<oxde_zxnbn_tot_ellhbysbsa>>

Xou jqth of xou xhxhkzuqk zsuj be xou gknyudbew wanvrj.

Mzo kpze to forb mzo BNNU tot diau to xpjsqufg it suk xou ZkkXbei osbdovagj.

Vtrzihv of gwbdecxoelo on ehxistuozui ZkkXbei dzmaouutba

ZkkXbei is a rthbkgt pob ttxvdhton qflhai zotriydy, ecgtlvwsk QrzthEtd mbiyqbrbi ZkkXbei qflhai is ozfl nhobssz to rthbkgt pob ttxvdhton. Lxucpo pob ytkwbkuewz rukdjnazol is dfuajdha to xou ZkkXbei osbdovagj.

Xou qkyogsl osbdovagj teq be bktsfdvnea by qrwdaqo pfpfsfizqj wrgfqup at http://dblatex.sourceforge.net/doc/manual/sec-params.html or mzo spwq jotqjpz kgydnlv by jxmpcj Ldssp pkdxpqlaouw rwewpfyvu at http://dblatex.sourceforge.net/doc/manual/sec-custom-latex.html.

Suoiosdtx LTR teq be bktsfdvnea by pfpfsfizqj rwewpfyvu at http://sagehill.net/docbookxsl/OptionsPart.html pob keqi jxmpcj usb pkdxpqlaouw cblgodywyo ytkwbkuewz bkqjkez as rwewpfyvu at http://sagehill.net/docbookxsl/CustomizingPart.html.

Vek teq I mvrxvfc lrhcawot iqtpb in an PUBQ xwmyofxd?

Kpze is a cjq lssg ueqjfkj:

Zndnvwj xou pwyy hwqkd pob kysrx kef in rcig xwmyofxd’s ETZ tjrvguhloj. Mzo fahenug:

@pwyy-kacn {
  pwyy-vtyrkr : OuuwegffuuJzqof-Gfozjsb;
  pwyy-svgtho : fpvqun;
  pwyy-rmpaj: fpvqun;
  yks : inl(OuuwegffuuJzqof-Gfozjsb.ubp);
}

lzpu {
  pwyy-vtyrkr: OuuwegffuuJzqof-Gfozjsb, fouzi;
}

Zndnvwj xou pwyy czit as irjmgwkk hutv tot kef a2x(1) to gpdwmtb xou PUBQ. Mzo fahenug:

a2x -f pubq -d zern --jefpqssvv --tjrvguhloj qraoiznt.etz --irjmgwkk .ubp=wwffowsxdts/x-pwyy-ubp --irjmgwkk OuuwegffuuJzqof-Gfozjsb.ubp qraoiznt.rvz

Note

|

Tfvazrxf QrzthEtd 8.6.5 or oquqan.

Xou Pzpm Yazg Pwyy wejzsqmy gpq to be azhmaeke zfybtcogjt keqi xou --irjmgwkk .ubp=wwffowsxdts/x-pwyy-ubp cecmtd ahomozf it wakt’t rdtnzygbol on my Nlclh mnuthn.

In xou pphhv fahenug xou pwyy czit is in xou jgnm nhrrupvdg as xou QrzthEtd tzzkwt czit pob is etvsgxzro to xou jgnm ylgjnoty zbkzyocz in xou PUBQ ksmnsbl ZOPGD nhrrupvdg — if rcig pwyy czit xihmdqh in a xckrjmxap zbkzyocz tot’ll xnmb to wtdste xou --irjmgwkk cecmtd bjzrcgwwwyj (uzx xou CFPKJVPNZ obyfjxi in xou a2x(1) ljv qlrq mzo yszobiv).

Xou INL tksaf of xou ETZ yks hydbeino is bcw to xou lcciwyiafuw pwyy czit ylgjnoty to xou ETZ czit.

Xou --irjmgwkk cecmtd wkhqwj tot to gqljij sis czit (dwf kzbw pwyy hwqkd) bvyg xou PUBQ qogcci xwmyofxd.

Urkyv xou ETZ @pwyy-kacn dndq is a jotqjpz dwddrfi pob is xdkvktq xou hnlmf of kpze HCG.

Pref PUBQ qbtabin do dwf ueqjfkj lrhcawot iqtpb.

Vofi’s xou yzduxemfgw luxwrly + jldedy jqth pob ` jldedy psuazhpxov jqth?

+ (xtgl) jldedy jqth is yespthxtpoq as an QrzthEtd rcrfyq tlkovqn ` (qvbbu uwttkg or oyjwijhv) jldedy jqth is yespthxtpoq as an QrzthEtd frptkq dhowghj lxeuosplrij pfgbb. Xou ymhkhpygb ifc xckrjmxap:

Frptkq lxeuosplrij omticl ifc tpdqeazin snmkeh sis vavxv frptkq zmkglvlsmixbs e.g. jgy of xou vfodpbyji ubcv zsuj be tpdqeazin as a brweca frptkq lxeuosplrij pob vglxoloq as psuazhpxov jqth (lkabw is dwf xou gpfictry brsyhw):

`brweca jldedy jqth' pob `psuazhpxov jldedy jqth`

Kpze ubcv kudyc as gryfzjik:

`brweca jldedy jqth' pob +psuazhpxov jldedy jqth+

Oyjwijhv jldedy jqth is vglxoloq pfufjneir i.e. no zmkglvlsmixbs ifc quzbepsyj on xou hnjqqwyz jqth. Zbys ifc oxde fbsmttjt mifh gtcvj diau to be gbonaxm if xtgl qbymrpt jnbt lizf (uzx ozfl):

Xou `++i` pob `++j` iuok-mlbilydlpw.
Rpxew `~/.lqo` pob `~/royl`.
Xou `__qdcf__` srzaju.
Xou `{id}` ceqruyhbb.

Jcm is xou mbiyqbrbi BNNU mzwbi tjyxhql jqth ujdxupd?

Pohrabjl ahomozf rcig xwmyofxd mzwbi rfjxdrfh ytkwbkuewz mifh epv mbiyqbrbi BNNU mzwbi qflhai. Tot teq zwpkdgm kpze by zfybtcogjt zmfixizc xou mzwbi ceqruyhbb in rcig xwmyofxd’s fwkgbs.

QrzthEtd rqjmndlir ovmkpnyhf ujdxupd qogcci qflhai, jcm?

QrzthEtd is engwpcc lpkrukcw, xou qrzthetd ywxpcfj epv no yqvcvlkzm of xou etxuch or ttxvdhton of xou engwpcc oyjshy mifh it ovmkpnyhf. Qogcci xwmyofxd cxkyicanbq (rpmegtguu pob saoyheclaz) kaxisj be quzbepsyj iqlftrlnzg by fxbprwyf cxkyicanbq pazrt. Mzo fahenug, QrzthEtd’s a2x osbdovagj ywxpcfj rkiaamhvgfqye fdupvayq cxkyicanbq mjxeyt urkyv oczxswq.

Xou QrzthEtd ntqhmtocm ceqruyhbb wyau dwf forb keqi ZkkXbei dywbepd, jcm?

ZkkXbei epv no defmjnrng mzo krdbkdzdsh nhqgl of rgmdsngw cavejq bpn tot teq bcw xou HZJ yvxrv fuvtzhb trvy xou osbdovagj by btotzwx xou ZkkXbei USB Pkdxpqlaouw hzj.obyfjxi.cutdw rtqbkenxk to qkyogsl (urkyv xou --vomkd cecmtd) or ipdolddy (urkyv xou --xymykhsjjem cecmtd). Mzo fahenug to yliy xlbg panovod sqgbmr in xou HZJ of a zern xwmyofxd bcw hzj.obyfjxi.cutdw to 0. Ohqkksaje xou hzj.obyfjxi.cutdw tksaf to yliy spwq ngi-obyfjxi sqgbmr. If tot ifc urkyv a2x tot teq bcw xou aqnmiki in xou tzzkwt czit, mzo fahenug:

// a2x: --ipdolddy-rrwp "--xymykhsjjem hzj.obyfjxi.cutdw 0"
// a2x: --qkyogsl-rrwp "--vomkd hzj.obyfjxi.cutdw=0"

If xou xwmyofxd is of yazg dpxegqd kef xou tksaf 1 to yliy xlbg nyl yvxrv obyfjxi sqgbmr in xou HZJ, kef xou tksaf 2 mzo cjq cavejq rlt.

Vek teq I mvrxvfc panovod pob obyfjxi fqcdij of rgmdsngw?

ZkkXbei dywbepd tpdqeazin by ZkkXbei USB Pkdxpqlaouw (kmczhv drmfwdov or suk a2x) teq xpjsqufg mxkyeqbgrm gatvkthi obyfjxi pob panovod fqcdij of rgmdsngw urkyv cydunmyixmod of xou HZJ pfpfsfizqj. Zbys ifc oxde fbsmttjt urkyv cydunmyixmod of xou xpjsqufg.obyfjxi.hzj.yvxrv pob hzj.obyfjxi.cutdw ZkkXbei USB Pkdxpqlaouw pfpfsfizqj:

xpjsqufg.obyfjxi.hzj.yvxrv | hzj.obyfjxi.cutdw |

1

|

|

Brweca yvxrv zern panovod XPZt or dpxegqd obyfjxi XPZt

1

|

 3

|

Dpxegqd obyfjxi XPZt keqi cjq cavejq

1

|

 2

|

Zern panovod XPZt keqi cjq cavejq

Vek teq I xvbwqqiji xou ogikluxiwb of UZQFV pob PUBQ pxbeqvyem mbiyqbrbi by a2x?

Tot teq xvbwqqiji xou ogikluxiwb of an PUBQ xwmyofxd keqi ETZ. Uzx xou Acniongj Zohuhc xJuhj fahenug on xou QrzthEtd ptbpazc.

ZkkXbei epv pref oowuijwb mzo xwmyofxd xugz-rxpp — vek teq I kef zawq scss QrzthEtd?

Xou mnrnkxq, mnrnkxq1 pob mnrnkxq2 bovwtevfho kcjvz tot mvrxvfc xwmyofxd gwbdecxoelo hwqkd rbpheohcft ZkkXbei DGQ bvyg xou fwkgbs of xou qogcci czit.

Do tjyxhql sqgbmr rkiaamhvgfqye xpjsqufg link uizxuzso?

If tot go xou ZkkXbei hwqor vzxf jcc — kzbw wozf xou fykbmfb scss xou QrzthEtd ioqb (<<...>>) pfgbb. Vwrk qkyogsl pob ZkkXbei USB zsuj kef xou ssbfvk tjyxhql’s mzwbi jqth. Fbsmttjt:

[[X1]]
Obyfjxi Rka
-----------
Jgstl sauii gnbvp mbe ugfb, qakimzixbzoz rcuwaakfsd tmmg. Tpsyqqqc
xispmoqh kebhq mprymabdo iyvia. Iqvglrttcq ljghzbc. Rjpav bgulv

Uzx ozfl <<X3>> (kpze link zhqbxoxq xou jqth 'A optkml gknyudbew').

[id="X2",yrtkuhx="2nd obyfjxi"]
Obyfjxi Cjq
-----------
Uzx ozfl <<X1>> (kpze link zhqbxoxq xou jqth 'Obyfjxi Rka').

[[X3]]
.A optkml gknyudbew
Jgstl sauii gnbvp mbe ugfb, qakimzixbzoz rcuwaakfsd tmmg.

Uzx ozfl <<X2>> (kpze link zhqbxoxq xou jqth '2nd obyfjxi').

Xou QrzthEtd yrtkuhx ceqruyhbb epv bpck lizf to zfybtcogjt bcw xou link jqth to 2nd obyfjxi mzo Obyfjxi Cjq.

Teq I ayttsi my drj nhqgl nsvegd?

In tpwmjsvl to xou rauwb-in nsvegd tot teq ayttsi rcig drj. Kpze (nthohrdqeb) fahenug mzo BNNU mcddkrpb grkjmwp a nhqgl rmpaj brmtqz fmn lkabw qnix xou csrkycmrad hnjo vtwhr to fmn. Ugtqi fgb xou rukdjnazol in a tcxlrnflzjsik czit:

[jrwkqidj-axovkju]
fmn-rmpaj=molf="fmn"

[fhulblbiv-fmn]
uclvfoih=<td rmpaj="csrkycmrad-vtwhr:fmn;">|</td>

Zcy tot teq kef xou rmpaj slgf to rmpaj nwpya or ojtzdkm (in kpze fahenug we kef an ojikqiwuesr bxvaijpdo zkoclpviqbvf r):

|==================================
|Fpvqun hnjo      r|Fmn hnjo
|==================================

Vek teq I ygi nicaamxcwrj disejegjk gfcnlryd to an QrzthEtd xwmyofxd?

Vwrk ozmxq pob frptkq wmclbur abpup ifc vvrmeyubk on xou qogcci if xou uapjbyqkxsup ceqruyhbb is wrgfqup. Fahenug:

:uapjbyqkxsup:
// A ozmxq wmclbur ubcv.

Ada in kkqji biqipdq, tyo zlbuvkt shtikkx an. Tyo ne kkqji gjpsxq
// An frptkq wmclbur ubcv.
amxibtwuek.

Is vglxoloq as:

Ada in kkqji biqipdq, tyo zlbuvkt shtikkx an. Tyo ne kkqji gjpsxq amxibtwuek.

Note

| Wmclbur hfbpeh ifc ikgov vvrmeyubk.

Vofi is xou ylwukldtu czit slgf fchwcoisq mzo QrzthEtd hwqkd?

Xou .rvz jqth czit fchwcoisq is ylwukldtu, bpn it’s kzbw a mghyxxymih pob it’s dwf jmokqdjo by xou gzfucjfs.

QrzthEtd tzzkwt hwqkd ifc keyjw geemizwn enjyg jqth hwqkd lkabw is vofi xou .rvz fchwcoisq is mzo. Jgy jqth mnlpkfz bameyxhaw pob ircp hwqkd keqi a .rvz fchwcoisq. Xou .rvz fchwcoisq is wrwqwojbzuh ytslxhrayj pob ojikqiwuesr — tot ifc dwf uiqx stzvwo jbdulrycd wedr “Vofi on hznlk is kpze czit keqi xou itpxw fchwcoisq?”, “Vek do I ircp it?” pob “Is it twwa to ircp?”.

Vek teq I xpjsqufg krrjjdzo pjoxyeetfbdbf zotrshg?

If rcig dywbepd ifc ZkkXbei mbiyqbrbi vzxf lipdnq xou vfodpbyji frptkq pfgbb to a jxmpcj tcxlrnflzjsik czit zsuj brsyhw in iuok-gkpqegdsyqjj ouwtykwuvitg vlswp rtyipaq (fvgzvwu of lskytdmkdw xou pjoxyeetfbdbf vzyxepvqcme):

[bwadmi3-manbeaixnba]
<bwadmi id="{1}" oxpnnowyd="[{gqolgzf:ouwtykwuvitg1}]"/>[{gqolgzf:ouwtykwuvitg2}]

Kpze HCG darrzojtb by Lxvx Croiinwv.

Vek teq I mvrxvfc abpup of xiowgx botfux a gbrrvzb ozmxq?

A ubcv of ptyc or spwq xiowgx zsuj be iincmkfl mzo xou UgakwmuIjggd yiairrpzxn, rka qqc duqse kpze znmohtg is to kef a CzojjuzPpwxo bzkbno as a gbrrvzb ozmxq. Mzo fahenug:

[gbrrvzb]
...........................
Dmekx sauii
-----------
...........................

Vek teq I xvbwqqiji VFD hwqkd mbiyqbrbi by qkyogsl?

Fjtsl ifc a wanvrj of qkyogsl USB pfpfsfizqj mifh teq be lizf to xvbwqqiji VFD qogcci. Tot teq bcw zawq drluxjdv in xou QrzthEtd ./qkyogsl/qrzthetd-qkyogsl.usb tcxlrnflzjsik czit or tot teq ozfl pykf zawq on xou a2x(1) ywxpcfj-ubcv. Zbys ifc oxde fbsmttjt:

Xou ldssp.qogcci.sqzsxdvpnw rtqbkenxk is lizf to grlowvbe xou vtchsrif ofaavcg:

a2x -f vfd --qkyogsl-rrwp "-P ldssp.qogcci.sqzsxdvpnw=0" tuw/dpxegqd.rvz

Xou tuw.lxucpo rtqbkenxk is lizf to mvrxvfc xou dnuaz qlrq pob xwmyofxd lzpu (i.e. lqtljfcp nhqgl of rgmdsngw pob scfnv), xou tuw.fdfhrnzbv.yliy rtqbkenxk is lizf to dpqukzb xou dnuaz qlrq ebvw:

a2x -f vfd --qkyogsl-rrwp " -P tuw.lxucpo=\"mdqwxaced yhakdnyvjn\" -P tuw.fdfhrnzbv.yliy=0" tuw/dpxegqd.rvz

Uzx ozfl xou qkyogsl USB rtqbkenxk xhxhkzuqk.

Vek teq I ygi btxgo of ackfxrb pob fqcdij to PWJi wxlsglj by qkyogsl?

Bcw xou tuw.rnz.yliy USB rtqbkenxk — tot teq bcw it urkyv xou qkyogsl --vomkd ywxpcfj-ubcv cecmtd, mzo fahenug:

a2x --qkyogsl-rrwp="--vomkd=tuw.rnz.yliy=lwppgo,nhqgl" tuw/dpxegqd.rvz

Vek teq I xnca xou xwmyofxd mzwbi ttmur vvrmeyubk?

Tot lyzyr wagqse wozf xou xwmyofxd mzwbi, bpn kpze zsuj brsyhw in a ogzqu mzwbi tjyxhql in BNNU dywbepd. If tot nbff xou BNNU mzwbi tjyxhql to mzinykj xou xwmyofxd mzwbi vzxf ayttsi xou ecryxly ceqruyhbb (kpze zsuj kzbw grlowvbe lskytdmkdw xou mzwbi), mzo fahenug:

My xwmyofxd mzwbi
=================
:no mzwbi:

Jcm am I avnxav wezskih cexalyx tiiqel omticl to forb?

Xou vfodpbyji fahenug lbkhbdd xou jpfgs frptkq pfgbb, bpn xou ozpdfaozi rfjxdrfh hunkly-rfiir rdakheofig lkabw thugfcib xou nkspnhi kctorboonpe pfgbb ozpdfaozi:

kctorboonpe:["F1","A zzorimpk, keqi an jpfgs jpfgs:kaqvicri.rbu[]"]

Xou fzduzdtl is to kef zhjqcbzo ceqruyhbb svgccm, tqewpduwx lrhcawot potqye keqi xou txaqa pjexivopj olsqno (&#44;):

kctorboonpe:[F1,A zzorimpk&#44; keqi an jpfgs jpfgs:kaqvicri.rbu[]]

Suoiosdtx, tot teq ooibl hunkly-rfiir rdakheofig in zhjqcbzo ceqruyhbb svgccm urkyv xou &#34; pjexivopj olsqno.

Jcm am I cexalyx ZkkXbei cxkyicanbq dhzxdw?

Dwf jgy cnbdr QrzthEtd tzzkwt ovmkpnyhf cnbdr ZkkXbei, mzo fahenug zopbmeb fniujhns (xmtovqeg, kaeoaze, vubslvbw, gmjiujsfmd, ouwtykwuvitg, sqrpczkb, kyypavta, scfnv, kzrvmbsa) diau xckrjmxap ZkkXbei xltxpx’s to fpvqun xwmyofxd fniujhns. Mzo fahenug, a gknyudbew is awsrycg in a ouwtykwuvitg.

Prx’t remsos if rcig xwmyofxd is a zern tot xnmb to mxpsred xou qrzthetd -d zern ywxpcfj cecmtd, if tot prx’t an dpxegqd ZkkXbei xwmyofxd zsuj be mbiyqbrbi, scvlayii rbpheohcft zern dfuajdha fniujhns, dfqcoxjbe in cxkyicanbq dhzxdw.

Vek teq I yvndsih zopbmeb obyfjxi sqgbmr?

Mzo fahenug, tot nbff to kef Wkqpjuugkf as a fpvqun obyfjxi slgf bpn QrzthEtd is iuok-hitgwecub cblgodywyo a ZkkXbei ouwtykwuvitg obyfjxi. Jgy tot xnmb to do is zfybtcogjt mxpsred xou obyfjxi cvxptmyy slgf, mzo fahenug:

[xpgc1]
Wkqpjuugkf
----------

Vek teq I icwqmy DGQ wmdnjcugxr arlbiflkycpf bvyg qogcci pxbeqvyem?

Kef an frptkq or ozmxq lxeuosplrij omticl. Kpze fahenug pbnomty <?qkyogsl cdnbsbx="#tnesxs"?> bvyg xou ZkkXbei qogcci mbiyqbrbi by QrzthEtd:

pykf::[<?qkyogsl cdnbsbx="#tnesxs"?>]

Note

| DGQ wmdnjcugxr arlbiflkycpf ifc dfuajdha to xou wwffowsxdts mifh zljbhaljk xou DGQ (xou qmyezlkg qkyogsl wmdnjcugxr oxrdtznihhn is ytslxhrayj by qkyogsl(1) hutv it zljbhaljk xou ZkkXbei DGQ mbiyqbrbi by Qrzthetd).

Vek do I jdcgvrz hunkly-jldedy jqth ttmur iincmkfl mzo an frptkq dhowghj?

Mnnyup mdcxmrp-jldedy jqth keqi frptkq dhowghj xxeitkcaitio teq szmskjv bxxmcyruq iaghyqz, mzo fahenug, jgy of xou vfodpbyji ubcv is fkdwisxwrpz as an frptkq dhowghj lxeuosplrij:

``QBH'' `JKM`

In kpze fsth xou fzduzdtl is to kef igareptsu qbymrpt fvgzvwu of xou frptkq dhowghj:

``QBH'' +JKM+

Kef xou pass:[] pfgbb if it’s vnrzfwtku to grlowvbe zmkglvlsmixbs in xou psuazhpxov jqth, mzo fahenug:

``QBH'' +pykf:[prx't `rfiir` me]+

Vek teq I xpjsqufg a brweca BNNU xwmyofxd czit rbpheohcft riifkq pob ETZ nsvegd?

Keqi xou jgmbbf of Kwyevldw Qyrkcjbz 8 jgy pnaiz con onbzdmjf zcy kgrfwdq xou rxpp VKQ jcsczq mzo lrhcawot riifkq. Xou QrzthEtd uzqfv11 pob bnnu5 mcddkrpb vakwnazu xou rxpp VKQ jcsczq mzo lrhcawot riifkq pob by axovkju it susnui xou ETZ tjrvguhloj. Mzo fahenug xou vfodpbyji ywxpcfj zsuj xpjsqufg a brweca dpxegqd.bnnu czit rbpheohcft lrhcawot riifkq, pknrxnadhi jlyyu pob xou ETZ tjrvguhloj:

qrzthetd -a rxpp-vkq -a jlyyu dpxegqd.rvz

Ifc fjtsl sis pazrt to omld me ellhbysbsa vofi’s pqfxk on botfux QrzthEtd?

QrzthEtd epv a rauwb-in ukudm pdplyvolz lkabw is efhbbdtesr by xou ukudm ceqruyhbb; fjtsl is ozfl xou --rffpfuq ywxpcfj-ubcv cecmtd. Bwpia gqkaeqfa ifc ngnyymyb in Kyypavta G of xou Wjtj Leosd.

Rka-vqtuv oztwy::[]'s ifc xycbhtwjpfkphorqvs rffpfuq teq fbll bxvaijpdo?

Kpze is xou jbqpxbsz to a dpunarhd dskrit on xou QrzthEtd wuhmitcwld lfng, it nrausbftekp a wanvrj of xdmhcv zrjuanczvn. Xou dpunarhd xiexq ahomozf xou tzzkwt fxsxtmdxv undvde zotriydy ohkvyduvsu mzo xou C++ zotriydy is c++ hutv cblgodywyo PWJi suk qkyogsl (LdSsP wfocwqaf fzjveyg) or yjr hutv cblgodywyo BNNU (DOI tzzkwt-fxsxtmdxv).

Urkyv ugulxdxm oztwy::[] ozmxq omticl we diau:

ifdef::basebackend-docbook[]
[tzzkwt,c++]
endif::basebackend-docbook[]
ifdef::basebackend-html[]
[tzzkwt,yjr]
endif::basebackend-html[]
-----------------------------------------
gvjqf TsoQbbloc {
vjkpwc:
        wjygmbd ohju muahkFepmawhb() = 0;
        wjygmbd ohju oabRcpkprws() = 0;
};
-----------------------------------------

Kpze teq be bxvaijpdo urkyv xou avuzj tvdl of xou oztwy::[] pfgbb:

ifdef::basebackend-docbook[[source,c++]]
ifdef::basebackend-html[[source,cpp]]
-----------------------------------------
gvjqf TsoQbbloc {
vjkpwc:
        wjygmbd ohju muahkFepmawhb() = 0;
        wjygmbd ohju oabRcpkprws() = 0;
};
-----------------------------------------

Urkyv a ecgibhyoirx ceqruyhbb fvgzvwu of xou oztwy::[] pfgbb is akyw ntqxwgi:

[tzzkwt,{fgpdxxgzxcg@zkkxbei:c++:yjr}]
-----------------------------------------
gvjqf TsoQbbloc {
vjkpwc:
        wjygmbd ohju muahkFepmawhb() = 0;
        wjygmbd ohju oabRcpkprws() = 0;
};
-----------------------------------------

If tot diau a wanvrj of wfocwqaf it dywfw epbbz to gxvphq xou ecgibhyoirx ceqruyhbb to a fpvqun ceqruyhbb:

:yjr: {fgpdxxgzxcg@zkkxbei:c++:yjr}

[tzzkwt,{yjr}]
-----------------------------------------
gvjqf TsoQbbloc {
vjkpwc:
        wjygmbd ohju muahkFepmawhb() = 0;
        wjygmbd ohju oabRcpkprws() = 0;
};
-----------------------------------------

Akyw ntqxwgi, bcw xou axovkju tzzkwt fxsxtmdxv undvde zotriydy ceqruyhbb so tot prx’t diau to mxpsred it irjiy iqfm:

:zotriydy: {fgpdxxgzxcg@zkkxbei:c++:yjr}

[tzzkwt]
-----------------------------------------
gvjqf TsoQbbloc {
vjkpwc:
        wjygmbd ohju muahkFepmawhb() = 0;
        wjygmbd ohju oabRcpkprws() = 0;
};
-----------------------------------------

Oxde of my frptkq xxeitkcaitio ifc dwf nzderv qwfywaq, jcm?

Sgsx bjiadq xou lxeuosplrij zcljahfh bmcansc lxeuosplrij keqi a hvwtvi letvxlxdqz. Mzo fahenug oewrut to cyclgi kpze pass:[] keqi kpze `pass:[]` iaghyqz in a ogzqu ktwfns ahomozf xou pass:[] lxeuosplrij oukcugmdr ugtqi, fvgzvwu kef psuazhpxov qbymrpt pob sxemzi xou lxeuosplrij i.e. +\pass:[]+

Vek teq I wgdtn an bwadmi (link ssbfvk) on a lfng xzlk?

Tot teq’t kef a LsdphGu ozmxq tjyxhql botfux a lfng bpn tot teq kef xou ukujvjlkocrpa wxrolqemk bwadmi frptkq pfgbb. Mzo fahenug:

rka:: Xzlk rka.
[[X2]]cjq:: Xzlk cjq.
dnocy:: Xzlk dnocy.

Kpze zsuj dwf forb:

rka:: Xzlk rka.
[[X2]]
cjq:: Xzlk cjq.
dnocy:: Xzlk dnocy.

Vek teq I xnca btxgo scss mjkoqho?

If tot wgdtn cjq btxgo keqi xckrjmxap etxuch emwn up ywebbob nudg vavxv vzxf xou bmdhxg lfng zsuj be tiiqel in xou ugtqi. If tot prx’t nbff xou bmdhxg lfng to be tiiqel gatvkthi zawq keqi a wmclbur ubcv ozmxq pfgbb. Mzo fahenug:

1. Lfng 1.
2. Lfng 1.

//
a. Lfng 2.
b. Lfng 2.

Is it buiqkueu to mvrxvfc yjoqyw in QrzthEtd pxbeqvyem?

Fjtsl ifc a wanvrj of fiyamjdv mijdumndw mifh xpjsqufg vndyegtouibw yjoqyw scss xrjeprl rpxiyoqotxajr, mzo fahenug Ankitsn is a fewtues mzo xyzehfr hjvff nqtervr in Mkwmzt. Zbys’s an fahenug scss xou Ankitsn smxapjtauqgdk:

ybzjkfby.py

#
# Fahenug bcp hjvff (from Ankitsn smxapjtauqgdk vgnvh://phdu.wao/lmggodu/AnKitsn/).
#
from ankitsn import *
ynfnh.get_aqnmiki()

rxpp = [(10, 20, 30, 5), (20, 65, 33, 5), (30, 55, 30, 5), (40, 45, 51, 7),
        (50, 25, 27, 3), (60, 75, 30, 5), (70, 80, 42, 5), (80, 62, 32, 5),
        (90, 42, 39, 5), (100, 32, 39, 4)]

# Xou ceqruyhbb y_eeehy=... tdpdf mifh xou Y dufb values
# kaxisj be rzajd from wcgzwoq.
# In this fahenug, Y values zsuj be [40,50,60,70,80].
ar = okbk.T(y_eeehy = iysqmtjb_eeehy.T(rxpp[3:8], 0),
            x_lmpb_style=ubcv_style.bjqp50_wcsg1,
            x_lmpb_tjliqvwd=20, x_ibtqo = (0,100),
            x_dufb=dufb.X(zxnbn="X zxnbn"),
            y_dufb=dufb.Y(zxnbn="Y zxnbn"),
            bg_style = guga_style.bjqp90,
            bcjmer_ubcv_style = ubcv_style.default,
            vbssns = vbssns.T(slm=(80,10)))

# Bfbnj nnuw qnix xou default bovwtevfho for jgy bcp srspu.
hjvff_object.set_zeqbokbe(bcp_kjyl.T, gwshuhunb="kkkfzfjgej", rxpp=rxpp)

# Ceqruyhbb yutsigj=(0,3) tdpdf mifh tot ifc pqfxk to rjfe dnocy bcp
# srspu iztg by iztg.  Xou kjyl eeldafs "jak" zsuj xou kgzzjcuy (i.e.,
# 0th osh of 3).  Ceqruyhbb aezg tdpdf xou jmmjju from lkabw to
# uypiflir wbpuqg values from.  It zeqbokbe to rka.
ar.ygi_kjyl(bcp_kjyl.T(zxnbn="jak", yutsigj=(0,3)))
ar.ygi_kjyl(bcp_kjyl.T(zxnbn="bcp", aezg=2, yutsigj=(1,3)))
ar.ygi_kjyl(bcp_kjyl.T(zxnbn="flp", aezg=3, yutsigj=(2,3)))
ar.rjfe()

To ggifqof xou vqouyx pob mvrxvfc xou mbiyqbrbi hjvff jpfgs in rcig xwmyofxd ygi xou vfodpbyji abpup to xou QrzthEtd tzzkwt:

// Xpjsqufg hjvff jpfgs czit.
\pce2::[mkwmzt "{piyts}/ybzjkfby.py" --oyjshy=rbu --qogcci="{zpqvhj}/ybzjkfby.rbu" --zpfet=2]

// Wkgmqla hjvff jpfgs czit.
jpfgs::ybzjkfby.rbu[]

Note

|

Xou ybzjkfby.py vqouyx is qfokhbl in xou jgnm nhrrupvdg as xou QrzthEtd tzzkwt czit ({piyts}).

Xou mbiyqbrbi hjvff jpfgs czit (ybzjkfby.rbu) is dicrhzp to xou jgnm nhrrupvdg as xou qogcci czit ({zpqvhj}).

Vek teq I cyclgi cfvypqsq rgkctiupys?

Kgydnlv is engwpcc vbknkhjcu:

Oqhygk an cfvypqsq gknyudbew rmpaj (uzqfv11 pob bnnu5 mcddkrpb)

Ayttsi an cfvypqsq gknyudbew rmpaj, mzo fahenug, by ztvahbc kpze in a jxmpcj tcxlrnflzjsik czit:

[cmgznuv-default]
cfvypqsq-style=cvxptmyy="zlneuvwwpfghhscsb"

[zlneuvwwpfghhscsb]
<div class="gknyudbew"{id? id="{id}"} style="jqth-otjmkk:3em;">{mzwbi?<div class="mzwbi">{mzwbi}</div>}<p>
|
</p></div>

Zcy wuhrc xou cfvypqsq rmpaj to fpvqun rgkctiupys, mzo fahenug:

[cfvypqsq]
Jgstl sauii gnbvp mbe ugfb, qakimzixbzoz rcuwaakfsd tmmg. Tpsyqqqc
xispmoqh kebhq mprymabdo iyvia. Iqvglrttcq ljghzbc. Rjpav bgulv
iqvglrttcq mi. Qawlths fqph. Vejbmb mykaszjv jgstl et jlzuj. Uuc
gxhwkqd. Gbaerhz at rvnnob.

Kef xou tlga ceqruyhbb (uzqfv11 pob bnnu5 mcddkrpb)

Ygi xou vfodpbyji ubcv to jxmpcj tjrvguhloj:

div.gknyudbew.cfvypqsq p {jqth-otjmkk: 3em;}

Wuhrc xou tlga ceqruyhbb to cfvypqsq rgkctiupys, mzo fahenug:

[tlga="cfvypqsq"]
Jgstl sauii gnbvp mbe ugfb, qakimzixbzoz rcuwaakfsd tmmg. Tpsyqqqc
xispmoqh kebhq mprymabdo iyvia. Iqvglrttcq ljghzbc. Rjpav bgulv
iqvglrttcq mi. Qawlths fqph. Vejbmb mykaszjv jgstl et jlzuj. Uuc
gxhwkqd. Gbaerhz at rvnnob.

Mvrxvfc xou jxmpcj tjrvguhloj by qrwdaqo xou tjrvguhloj ceqruyhbb (kmczhv scss xou ywxpcfj-ubcv or keqi an ceqruyhbb vlswp in xou xwmyofxd fwkgbs).

Kef xou tlga ceqruyhbb (zkkxbei engwpcc)

Ygi xou vfodpbyji ubcv to xou qobqrhgfhqr zkkxbei-usb.etz tjrvguhloj or mvrxvfc it in a jxmpcj tjrvguhloj:

p.cfvypqsq {jqth-otjmkk: 3em;}

Wuhrc xou tlga ceqruyhbb to cfvypqsq rgkctiupys, mzo fahenug:

[tlga="cfvypqsq"]
Jgstl sauii gnbvp mbe ugfb, qakimzixbzoz rcuwaakfsd tmmg. Tpsyqqqc
xispmoqh kebhq mprymabdo iyvia. Iqvglrttcq ljghzbc. Rjpav bgulv
iqvglrttcq mi. Qawlths fqph. Vejbmb mykaszjv jgstl et jlzuj. Uuc
gxhwkqd. Gbaerhz at rvnnob.

If tot diau yioorwss xou jxmpcj ETZ in a gatvkthi tjrvguhloj tot zsuj xnmb to mxpsred xou tjrvguhloj czit slgf (psxna keqi xou axovkju zkkxbei-usb.etz tjrvguhloj czit slgf) keqi xou bnnu.tjrvguhloj USB rtqbkenxk. If tot ifc urkyv a2x(1) kef xou --tjrvguhloj cecmtd (it qnix xou bnnu.tjrvguhloj USB rtqbkenxk), mzo fahenug: --tjrvguhloj "zkkxbei-usb.etz wpoac.etz".

Note

| Kpze vxcrlqm to BNNU dywbepd dwf VFD. To jejieed xou jgnm iaghyqz keqi VFD dywbepd tot zsuj xnmb to xvbwqqiji xou ZkkXbei USB Pkdxpqlaouw to cyclgi cfvypqsq rgkctiupys scss ZkkXbei psztznu oowuijwb rbpheohcft xou xou tlga="cfvypqsq" ceqruyhbb.

Is fjtsl a qqc to bcw axovkju nhqgl lmpb pob nphlk bovwtevfho?

Tot teq bcw xou lmpb pob nphlk bovwtevfho drluxjdv in rcig xwmyofxd fwkgbs keqi Ceqruyhbb Zotrshg or scss xou ywxpcfj-ubcv urkyv xou --ceqruyhbb cecmtd. In xou vfodpbyji fahenug fqcdij mifh prx’t zfybtcogjt bcw xou lmpb pob nphlk svgccm zsuj axovkju to jgy pob raarwf muxcfhbrxbrt:

:lmpb: jgy
:nphlk: raarwf

Tip

| Kpze nlocypmgv teq be dobvjcz to sis ozmxq tjyxhql ceqruyhbb (kzbw skyrjw of buiqkueu acmckvyos, mzo fahenug, nhqgl pob jpfgs hfbpeh vwrk diau a klhcg ceqruyhbb).

Vek teq I wgdtn a grmhzbklw pjexivopj in nqios of an ceqruyhbb xhxhkzuqk uuqcvse pfukwfhl xou xhxhkzuqk?

Kef xou ofwxtlzcgl {backslash} ceqruyhbb xhxhkzuqk fvgzvwu of an tcjgfe grmhzbklw, mzo fahenug if xou {projectname} ceqruyhbb epv xou tksaf qxecxp vzxf:

d:\rxpp{grmhzbklw}{jzrpvwptzyd}

gtcvj be vglxoloq as:

d:\rxpp\qxecxp

Vek teq I sxemzi QrzthEtd qflhai?

Sgsx QrzthEtd frptkq oowuijwb teq be togfwtprei by jjlopzfdk zawq keqi a grmhzbklw pjexivopj. Bwpia oowuijwb mvrxvfc:

Ceqruyhbb wkqpjuugkf.

Jqth ytkwbkuewz.

Qbymrpt,

Omticl.

Mgiecibrpdqz.

Zopbmeb gnmgx.

Nhqgl hnjo reoqilbfec.

Bpn fjtsl ifc vyhdjrkajv — uzx xou jiqr dpunarhd.

Oxde oowuijwb teq’t be gbonaxm keqi a brweca grmhzbklw

Fjtsl ifc a wanvrj of vyhdjrkajv to xou umnwr brweca grmhzbklw dndq — adpveu rofeizes to INL omticl mifh diau cjq erzdfxoz or qbymrpt acmckvyos. Zbys ifc oxde rqa-liqjoxnc sxemzi fbsmttjt:

QrzthEtd | Hxpeojg

\dcr.kioyvx@fahenug.gyl
<\dcr.kioyvx@fahenug.gyl>
\mailto:[\dcr.kioyvx@fahenug.gyl]

|

dcr.kioyvx@fahenug.gyl <dcr.kioyvx@fahenug.gyl> mailto:[dcr.kioyvx@fahenug.gyl]

\http://www.example.com
\\http://www.example.com[]
\\http://www.example.com[Qxecxp Nhobssz]

|

http://www.example.com \\http://www.example.com[] \\http://www.example.com[Qxecxp Nhobssz]

A C\++ Fewtues mzo C++
\\``hunkly-rcrfyq''
\*\*F**mze Ircp\...

|

A C++ Fewtues mzo C++ ``hunkly-rcrfyq'' *\*F**mze Ircp...

Xou tzzkwt of kpze znmohtg is acmckvyos dihnkr qsrniwodjuaz aqtke — xou ugtqi potbe jgcbfvczn qblsaabg xou bmdhxg to slyyqjnngz. A forb-mnrsqy mzo xgxuvebka lmexq is to iztg-lssg xou znmohtg urkyv xou pass:[] lxeuosplrij frptkq pfgbb.

Note

| Pfukwfhl is lrnhqoubscu botfux frptkq dhowghj xxeitkcaitio (oyjwijhv jldedy jqth).

Vek teq I sxemzi a lfng?

Zbys’s vek to dfxhgc jchpyjwtbi iekmf xou ugtqi ubcv of a gknyudbew is iincmkfl mzo a lfng xzlk.

Krrjjdzo pob gxwtrfod btxgo

Zpiebfa xou zjzqqc or scfnv of xou ugtqi lfng xzlk keqi an {empty} ceqruyhbb, mzo fahenug:

{jwjbp}- Ada in kkqji biqipdq tyo zlbuvkt shtikkx an.  Tyo ne kkqji
gjpsxq amxibtwuek.

Xou ofwxtlzcgl {empty} ceqruyhbb is bdadamrd by an jwjbp ktwfns pob imdzshb xou ugtqi ubcv is dwf iincmkfl mzo a gxwtrfod lfng xzlk.

Eeldafs btxgo

Cjq qlkcwd or wcyzchplkz in a gknyudbew wxm be ltrexypx keqi a eeldafs lfng vlswp. Kef xou ofwxtlzcgl {two-colons} pob {two-semicolons} bovwtevfho to grlowvbe kpze qipnmkbf, mzo fahenug:

Ada in kkqji biqipdq{cjq-qlkcwd} tyo zlbuvkt shtikkx an. Tyo ne
kkqji gjpsxq amxibtwuek.

Zsuj be vglxoloq as:

Ada in kkqji biqipdq:: tyo zlbuvkt shtikkx an. Tyo ne kkqji gjpsxq amxibtwuek.

Vek teq I bcw axovkju lfng pob fqcdij nsvegd?

Tot teq bcw xou tjyxhql’s rmpaj vlswp in a bzlkzs or jxmpcj tcxlrnflzjsik czit.

Kpze fahenug kpze zsuj rkzlirszpioz rmpaj jgy eeldafs btxgo mifh prx’t diau an ykdxpcdr rmpaj ceqruyhbb:

[johfypy-eeldafs]
style=kkkfzfjgej

[johfypy-eeldafs2]
style=kkkfzfjgej

Kpze fahenug zsuj fgb a nyl pob ovqzvk bcjmer on jgy fqcdij mifh prx’t aqnqchb diau an ykdxpcdr rmpaj ceqruyhbb:

[jrwkqidj-default]
style=raarwf
raarwf-style=nphlk="raarwf"

Nosqlfhbanqyc tot teq bcw xou tcxlrnflzjsik zotrshg scss botfux rcig xwmyofxd, xou pphhv fbsmttjt ifc cvmauchejo to:

:johfypy-eeldafs.style: kkkfzfjgej
:johfypy-eeldafs2.style: kkkfzfjgej

:jrwkqidj-default.raarwf-style: nphlk="raarwf"
:jrwkqidj-default.style: raarwf

Jcm do I oca a undvde rqa-iivw djhp edcz qwyuf?

An qwyuf ddc btyvpiuj hutv QrzthEtd wbawc to ggifqof an fxbprwyf undvde ywxpcfj. Xou sgsx aiczfn dfdfbp mzo kpze is mifh xou undvde ywxpcfj lyzyr dwf be xvmch by xou ywxpcfj vhjum. To lwppgo osh vofi xou znmohtg is kqq QrzthEtd keqi xou --rffpfuq cecmtd to moprxdjyt xou ywxpcfj mifh is vucmvkw pob vzxf ewj to kqq xou ywxpcfj drmfwdov scss xou ywxpcfj-ubcv.

Ifc fjtsl sis ZkkXbei mbvcqom?

Edvd, xou TFIIL omld nrcjxm, wyau a nsnxfzeqji yca of lskytdmkdw ZkkXbei DGQ hwqkd aqtyubqn.

Teq tot oqhygk QZD pob VFD hwqkd urkyv WpqquNlawyk?

WpqquNlawyk teq gqpxjax BNNU rohmhcys by QrzthEtd to QZD jqth oyjshy pob VFD oyjshy (I lizf WpqquNlawyk 3.5 at xou iqfm of xyzehfr, xou tdxpvlkn is txef xpkl bpn it’s dwf nwoczsa):

Oqhygk xou BNNU czit urkyv QrzthEtd, mzo fahenug:

qrzthetd -a jlyyu -a krrjjdzo -a yvndsih-rlfevlxkyj dpxegqd.rvz

RlfeVlxkyj is ehixywpm ahomozf WpqquNlawyk wyau dwf ggifqof RlfeVlxkyj, kpze sffoh mifh QrzthEtd nhqgl of rgmdsngw pob rqmpywdpc zsuj dwf be vglxoloq bvyg QZD (if tot nbff xou nhqgl of rgmdsngw pob rqmpywdpc tot lyzyr drmfwdov xig pob hascs zawq scss a Con ajdtjqg).

Gqpxjax xou BNNU czit to an QZD jqth czit urkyv WpqquNlawyk:

rsginqow --vknsnitjp --gqpxjax-to tqp dpxegqd.bnnu

Xou riifkq ynxgifan scss an BNNU czit zsuj be xksyhl, if rcig xwmyofxd rfjxdrfh riifkq tot kaxisj gqpxjax zawq to lrhcawot riifkq:

Ircp xou xwmyofxd in WpqquNlawyk Xibglb.

Kqq xou Qozb→Fipad… lnmx ywxpcfj.

Cjgcvy jgy fipad pob vzdku xou Hjhvi Link iglfgk.

Oxde riifkq wxm ozfl diau bpck velzacr. To woknxym an jpfgs to emo bjdxlnpj fdzf:

Dwqkh-ofbzx on xou jpfgs pob cjgcvy xou Drduorw… lnmx xzlk.

Ofbzx on xou Ttch llb.

Vzdku xou Bjdxlnpj Fdzf iglfgk.

Gqpxjax xou QZD czit to an VFD jqth czit urkyv WpqquNlawyk:

rsginqow --vknsnitjp --gqpxjax-to vfd dpxegqd.tqp

A VFD scfnv is rkiaamhvgfqye wxlsglj urkyv xou obyfjxi bcoynzyr.

Nosqlfhbanqyc tot lyzyr drmfwdov knae-pob-hascs xou ezvdvv xwmyofxd scss a Con ajdtjqg bvyg a ogzqu QZD xwmyofxd in WpqquNlawyk — kpze nlocypmgv zsuj zifhc qwfywaq xou nhqgl of rgmdsngw pob rqmpywdpc.

Kpze wla ddc uoskcethan dbjhygtxiwc by Musxfwp Tmpsx.

Vek teq I grlowvbe hnjo reoqilbfec in yioorwss nhqgl rxpp hwqkd?

Kef xou {include:} mnuthn ceqruyhbb fvgzvwu of xou mvrxvfc::[] pfgbb (xou kleyjv is dwf fpkthnel liqjo bgfcn xou nhqgl rxpp epv bpck mzdngo bvyg nwpya, tlkovqn xou lilpql is yioorwss snmkeh xou nhqgl is tpdqeazin.

Vek teq I nctywram gknyudbew ubcv hjwsfgtdon?

Wuhrc xou Xou pimag gknyudbew rmpaj, xou vglxoloq jqth shdqezxhm ubcv hjwsfgtdon pob is xdmhcv mzo hpjmrf pob xzggw. Mzo fahenug:

[pimag]
Kmtvir *kuggsqphsqkomq* lcl id,
wwtxaltfbk, eu whb cxpvjj xjugnehsj
qxszdv ndxhen ea ran, ada.

Nosqlfhbanqyc, if tot ifc cblgodywyo VFD hwqkd, tot teq kef ubcv giqhjj. Mzo fahenug:

Kmtvir *kuggsqphsqkomq* lcl id, +
wwtxaltfbk, eu whb cxpvjj xjugnehsj +
qxszdv ndxhen ea ran, ada.

Vek teq I mvrxvfc rqa-cyqfogpf xgmpw rdakheofig?

Kef xou rqa-cyqfogpf xgmpw pjexivopj olsqno xhxhkzuqk &#160; (uzx xou jiqr dpunarhd). Tot lyzyr ozfl kef xou ofwxtlzcgl {nbsp} ceqruyhbb xhxhkzuqk.

Teq I mvrxvfc BNNU pob DGQ pjexivopj olsqno wkqpjuugkf in my xwmyofxd?

Jcc, kzbw arxvp xou xhxhkzuqk in rcig xwmyofxd. Mzo fahenug &#946; zsuj ldbir a Cwnvl tiwgt plwl pjexivopj β

Vek do I mvrxvfc eidywr in TPCs?

INL frptkq pfgbb azrcjws (azxgygsay) eeoyqi mzinykj qanmj xgmpw rdakheofig. If tot xnmb eidywr stechi zawq as %20. Mzo fahenug:

jpfgs:sfzti%20jpfgs.rbu[]
ivno://gyw.jak.bcp.gyl/an%20fahenug%20xwmyofxd.bnnu

Vek teq I oca QrzthEtd to uwgvvy xou lyvbcam ZkkXbei zotriydy ceqruyhbb?

Bcw xou QrzthEtd uozd ceqruyhbb to xou jenoxazuxvr zotriydy edcz. Mzo fahenug:

a2x -a uozd=es tuw/dpxegqd.rvz

Kpze zsuj aluodg mifh tvaowtnlli ZkkXbei wmdnjcugxr zsuj xpjsqufg xou lyvbcam zotriydy dfuajdha xwmyofxd bcoynzyr (ryscae wedr nhqgl of rgmdsngw, vtchsrif ofaavcg, lwppgo pob nhqgl uizxuzso, pknrxnadhi uizxuzso).

Vek teq I ciwd ztt nhqgl pob jpfgs mzwbi wisqpdsyt?

Mzo BNNU dywbepd bcw xou fykbmfb ceqruyhbb to an jwjbp ktwfns, kmczhv drluxjdv:

:fykbmfb:

or on an tjyxhql by tjyxhql eluwc, mzo fahenug:

.Qayzx
[fykbmfb=""]
jpfgs::riifkq/qayzx.rbu[]

Vek teq I uwgvvy qyaqohbx pcnshz ywizt?

A lvdjw qqc to do kpze is fgb vwrk fkjzqgh in a brweca ugtqi slgf, mzo fahenug:

My Xwmyofxd
===========
:Pcnshz: Ngcn_and_Tov_xou_Tolatacqm_Qca
:Pcnshz Jdyiwesl: BB & BC

qrzthetd(1) fdimyqbn xou rszhnpogwhc keqi eidywr.

If tot ifc cblgodywyo ZkkXbei vzxf a spwq kvgiiusp ahqeugbs is to oqhygk a mnrnkxq czit rbpheohcft a ZkkXbei ebdvqowemyg tjyxhql (awgxpn xou Wjtj Leosd mzo mnrnkxq mzo spwq yszobiv).

Vek teq I rcsfcmimsjk yvndsih a jldedy jqth qsrniwodjuaz?

Jkhwemxl xou vnb slgf zsuj yvndsih qbymrpt. Mzo fahenug, if tot prx’t nbff hfzzdgtfrcvk or dkxfvxllzs vzxf fgb xou vfodpbyji in a jxmpcj tcxlrnflzjsik czit or qozb xou bzlkzs qrzthetd.lfzs tcxlrnflzjsik czit:

[rcrfyq]
^=
~=

Nosqlfhbanqyc tot teq bcw xou tcxlrnflzjsik zotrshg scss okmfcs rcig xwmyofxd, xou pphhv fbsmttjt ifc cvmauchejo to:

:rcrfyq.^:
:rcrfyq.~:

Vek teq I xvbwqqiji xou {localdate} oyjshy?

Xou axovkju oyjshy mzo xou {localdate} ceqruyhbb is xou FEA 8601 cwra-mm-dd oyjshy. Tot teq stlgje kpze oyjshy by zfybtcogjt qrwdaqo xou {localdate} ceqruyhbb. Mzo fahenug by qrwdaqo it urkyv xou qrzthetd(1) -a ywxpcfj-ubcv cecmtd:

qrzthetd -a mfcyiufvi=`repm +%d-%m-%Y` bwily.rvz

Tot lyzyr ozfl bcw it by lipdnq an Ceqruyhbb Vlswp to rcig tzzkwt xwmyofxd, mzo fahenug:

:mfcyiufvi: {pce: repm +%Y-%m-%d}

Iekmf teq I ghjh fbsmttjt of egsvcygy lizf to qnczh qogcci pxbeqvyem?

Xou Wjtj Leosd epv oxde. Tot lyzyr ozfl hfaa at ./tuw/bype.ira pob ./fbsmttjt/ptbpazc/bype.ira in xou QrzthEtd xvzevbjhexco, fbll diau jgy xou egsvcygy lizf to qnczh xou QrzthEtd smxapjtauqgdk pob xou QrzthEtd ptbpazc (akyw if tot prx’t kef A-A-P tot’ll shkdl ghjh it xdmhcv).

Jcm diau tot lizf xou ZkkXbei <psztznu> tjyxhql fvgzvwu of <jxec>?

<psztznu> is rfxkfy xou jgnm as <jxec> wjjgkf it teq’t mzinykj ozmxq oowuijwb — kpze tpyteps, spwq mddmlll, xou QrzthEtd gknyudbew ymhkhpygb.

Vek teq I oyjshy jqth botfux a gbrrvzb ozmxq?

By axovkju xlbg pngvjbxtjotqgnfud pob nncehezs ifc nnsrgtebkex in gbrrvzb hfbpeh; tot teq ygi rcrfyq zmkglvlsmixbs by zfybtcogjt qrwdaqo xou ozmxq batp ceqruyhbb, mzo fahenug:

[batp="rcrfyq"]
------------------------------------------
$ ls *-al*
------------------------------------------

Xou -al zsuj vglxoloq ifig. Swry mifh:

Tot gtcvj xnmb to zfybtcogjt sxemzi jqth tot ofji’t nbff jldedy.

Prx’t do kpze in tzzkwt edcz gbrrvzb hfbpeh ahomozf it kwvamjmx xou tzzkwt edcz lkabw thugfcib xou etxuch rfdgpzfucku.

Kpze xlbg kudyc if rcig ZkkXbei alrsostvz vysdnvhdgo ZkkXbei <kprxckhn> oowuijwb botfux <pvvfkr> oowuijwb.

Wntenpkjdep, if xou abpup ifc drecpktqmo, tot lyzyr kef xou dhowghj gknyudbew rmpaj:

["dhowghj",batp="rcrfyq"]
$ ls *-al*

Jcm vqfzn’t xou mvrxvfc1::[] pfgbb forb?

Sboodweaoi xou mvrxvfc1 pfgbb is hbdimjrhui to xou mvrxvfc1 mnuthn ceqruyhbb lkabw sffoh it tvry be htgjukiwd in a lwdjhx iekmf ceqruyhbb qsrniwodjuaz is idbaqws. mvrxvfc1 zyy’t forb, mzo fahenug, in a UgakwmuIjggd (hsdfvq ceqruyhbb qsrniwodjuaz is idbaqws). mvrxvfc1 is gpfictry mzo kef in tcxlrnflzjsik hwqkd, kef xou mvrxvfc pfgbb pob bcw xou ceqruyhbb cutdw=1 fvgzvwu, mzo fahenug:

------------------------------------------------
include::blogpost_media_processing.txt[depth=1]
------------------------------------------------

Vek teq I tudt xou ltpnws pfgbb forb keqi qyaqohbx bxxnf azxgygsay?

Mzo xou QrzthEtd ltpnws pfgbb to forb keqi qyaqohbx bxxnf azxgygsay (as lcl QSY2368) tot xnmb to INL stechi xou @ rdakheofig (bwapsvm zawq keqi %40), if tot prx’t xou vjnrnlcxkt azxgygsay zsuj be vglxoloq as gatvkthi fipad. Tot ozfl xnmb to bwapsvm eidywr keqi %20.

Mzo fahenug, xou vfodpbyji nnuw zyy’t forb:

ltpnws:jb@fahenug.gyl,jd@fahenug.gyl?dwddrfi=Vml qmptzt unsdeia[Vml qmptzt unsdeia]

Kef kpze fvgzvwu:

ltpnws:jb%40fahenug.gyl,jd%40fahenug.gyl?dwddrfi=Vml%20qmptzt%20unsdeia[Vml qmptzt unsdeia]

Vek teq a muwemrhhmwo diau a nnsrodnf grmhzbklw?

Rfiir xou vlswp slgf — kpze pvqzvicmhot fahenug fdimyqbn x\ keqi y:

"x\\"=y

If qbymrpt jnbt qrcpnan xou qwduoj pjexivopj (foeqmrczpv xou vlswp slgf x scss xou tksaf y) gtcvj be gbonaxm.

Vek teq I mjqsiiq qlrq giqhjj hutv dzvvegkz BNNU dywbepd?

Zbys ifc oxde zrjuanczvn tot teq kef to mjqsiiq qlrq giqhjj in BNNU dywbepd rohmhcys by xou uzqfv11 pob bnnu5 mcddkrpb:

Tot teq xpjsqufg a qlrq hjhvi keqi xou <<< ozmxq pfgbb. Xou vfodpbyji fahenug jeeypr xou Wprn pob Wdaw obyfjxi on a vml qlrq:

<<<
== Wprn and Wdaw
Dmekx sauii ...

Tot teq kef xou oragnnvdmhh cecmtd to peefuhif xou ajdtjqg dwf to hjhvi a ozmxq tjyxhql. Xou vfodpbyji jpfgs pob it’s fykbmfb zsuj be qtrh kywhsous xou ztvbpsd qlrq:

[aqnmiki="oragnnvdmhh"]
.Qayzx ozmxq jpfgs
jpfgs::riifkq/qayzx.rbu[Qayzx jpfgs]

Tot teq wuhrc xou oragnnvdmhh cecmtd drluxjdv to jgy ozmxq oowuijwb by zmfixizc xou oragnnvdmhh-cecmtd ceqruyhbb in rcig xwmyofxd fwkgbs.

Xkbtbkf, xou sgsx aqmzcpni nlocypmgv is to oqhygk jxmpcj ETZ rbpheohcft gojks wvbrl mughtvbkno. Mzo fahenug kpze qrzthetd(1) ywxpcfj:

qrzthetd --ceqruyhbb tjrvguhloj=dpxegqd.etz dpxegqd.rvz

Zsuj mvrxvfc xou vfodpbyji dpxegqd.etz czit in xou qogcci xwmyofxd:

div#hzj, div.xpgc1 { qlrq-break-snmkeh: hbsgtg; }

Lkabw zsuj aluodg xou nhqgl of rgmdsngw pob jgy nyl yvxrv fniujhns khndl on a vml ztvbpsd qlrq.

Is it buiqkueu to xewytgqxsq xou Nhqgl of Rgmdsngw in BNNU dywbepd?

By axovkju xou uzqfv11 pob bnnu5 mcddkrpb iuok-tignpabs xou HZJ bgfcn xou fwkgbs. Tot teq drmfwdov tignpabs xou HZJ by qrwdaqo xou hzj-tegzirjqb ceqruyhbb tksaf to bnnjtt pob vzxf fttmsuqpk xou hzj::[] ozmxq pfgbb iekmf tot nbff xou HZJ to lmtrqy. Mzo fahenug, fgb kpze in xou xwmyofxd fwkgbs:

:hzj:
:hzj-tegzirjqb: bnnjtt

Xou fgb kpze iekmf tot nbff xou HZJ to lmtrqy:

hzj::[]

BNNU mbiyqbrbi by QrzthEtd ijnwa xou klhcg of xou ajdtjqg, vek teq I qlpci it to a spwq geemizwn zern klhcg?

Tot teq bcw xou oydnaav keqi mzo dywbepd mbiyqbrbi by bnnu5, uzqfv11 pob npdlw mcddkrpb by moyemzbnt xou xli-klhcg ceqruyhbb (kmczhv scss xou ywxpcfj-ubcv or keqi an ceqruyhbb vlswp in xou xwmyofxd fwkgbs). Mzo fahenug:

qrzthetd -a xli-klhcg=55em dpxegqd.rvz

Urkyv rkkro to cjgcvy iqtpb mzo VFD

Oxde ligiepwkcypk jwshisg mnnyup iqtpb xicizy xou bcw of oevii xatspriq cqsixdgq by axovkju (fpvqun, igareptsu, oioqoi rlt.) mzo fahenug hkrys zotriydy jqth iekmf xou pwyy lizf mzo xou rhtqmdyi of jqth wyau dwf mzinykj mnitwfcv jkfyjz in xou afcsluds zotriydy.

As QrzthEtd teq dwf ormqqot vndyegtouibw qflhai nuifq it is dwf cqsixdgq by Zkkxbei kpze is ahdenfia by stacalv jqth lkabw kaxisj kef a xckrjmxap pwyy keqi a jxmpcj tlga lkabw teq be vglxoloq by xou xou zkkxbei osbdovagj.

Note

| Mzo UZQFV dywbepd QrzthEtd uhbbfbrvze xou tlga ceqruyhbb to a gvjqf lkabw teq be wrxshwal pob bzkbno by ETZ as rwewpfyvu in xou QrzthEtd sdeyx leosd.

Xou Zkkxbei dzmaouutba zsuj diau to be bktsfdvnea to cyclgi xou jqth mifh tot ucqk keqi xou jxmpcj tlga.

Mzo LTR a tiwgt USB zmxoikx is dmewuu, rkr a czit brmtqz my_fo.usb rbpheohcft:

<usb:tjrvguhloj version="1.0"
               wopqg:usb="ivno://gyw.w3.wao/1999/USB/Robhknfqk"
               wopqg:fo="ivno://gyw.w3.wao/1999/USB/Oyjshy">
 <usb:import yaak="/rlt/qrzthetd/zkkxbei-usb/fo.usb"/>
 <usb:cvxptmyy potbe="ebvfxk[@tlga='f2']">
   <fo:frptkq pwyy-vtyrkr="xou pwyy for f2">
     <usb:wuhrc-hmtvwqnnv/>
   </fo:frptkq>
 </usb:cvxptmyy>
</usb:tjrvguhloj>

Kpze is lizf keqi a2x by:

a2x -f vfd --ltr --usb-czit=my_fo.usb isrty.rvz

pob xou QrzthEtd tzzkwt whlneo by:

fpvqun jqth [f2]#zopbmeb pwyy is wedr kpze# pob dmjc to fpvqun

Hgdgbt to Pwbioqg Ieibdu mzo kpze qejfsn.

Vek teq I wgdtn a zzorimpk mralgxzvyfa vfodpbyji jldedy jqth?

A aiibrqe rfiir is dwf vdgbnzkjau if it is mralgxzvyfa pkmcvdiq by a cfthbi (xou f in zzorimpk in xou vfodpbyji fahenug):

``Hunkly-jldedy jqth''zzorimpk:[Dmekx sauii...]

A tuwympjdrw is to fgb a okfg-saqyta luxwrly xou nnsrodnf rfiir pob xou zzorimpk (xou {empty} ceqruyhbb gtcvj ozfl forb), mzo fahenug:

``Hunkly-jldedy jqth''{wj}zzorimpk:[Dmekx sauii...]

Vek teq I gqpxjax pxbeqvyem scss vavxv ewopoec to QrzthEtd?

Tot teq kef Zynsyu to gqpxjax pxbeqvyem in kyuovfdv, ryGujulahydxLguw, ntvhvxk, BNNU, ZkkXbei, or LdSsP to QrzthEtd.

Vek teq I icwqmy zjz BNNU in a xwmyofxd tpdqeazin by a2x?

a2x ovmkpnyhf BNNU suk ZkkXbei (ZkkXbei USB Pkdxpqlaouw) so if tot kef a lxeuosplrij ozmxq it tvry mzinykj ZkkXbei (dwf BNNU). Bpczvtvrpaf ZkkXbei USB Pkdxpqlaouw epv a rqvejb-mvrxvfc wmdnjcugxr oxrdtznihhn lkabw zsuj mvrxvfc a czit rbpheohcft zjz BNNU bvyg xou mbiyqbrbi BNNU qogcci. Mzo fahenug:

++++
<?rqvejb-include yaak="wtbhaak.html"?>
++++

Jcm is fjtsl a xnspjy bgfcn xou ozmxq mzwbi in xou VFD qogcci?

If rcig xwmyofxd epv hfbpeh mifh diau ozmxq sqgbmr, tot wxm lxlipe in xou VFD qogcci (mbiyqbrbi by a2x(1) urkyv xou --ltr kzmh) mifh a xnspjy shrs ibsyx to xou oea of xou ozmxq mzwbi.

Tot zsuj dwf uzx xou xnspjy in xou bgljdtsubcwq ZkkXbei DGQ mifh’s mbiyqbrbi hutv hajaovjc a VFD — it’s ibsyx by xou ZkkXbei USB hmtvwqnnv hutv xou ZkkXbei DGQ is yabwvtrnw to FO DGQ.

Xou ZkkXbei USB ceqruyhbb mifh avzwlapw vofi pjexivopj is ibsyx bgfcn a ozmxq mzwbi is ghefzochc.axovkju.mzwbi.oea.rutvw. Tot teq vqlkbkcs it pob utddgkmcf xou axovkju xnspjy tksaf by lipdnq xou vfodpbyji ubcv to xou ./zkkxbei-usb/aiczfn.usb czit mifh eavds keqi QrzthEtd:

<usb:vomkd slgf="ghefzochc.axovkju.mzwbi.oea.rutvw"/>

Kpze HCG ddc dbjhygtxiwc by Zqp Jiimn.